Okay, good morning. So today we do Islam.
好的，早上好。今天我们来讲伊斯兰。
Some quick facts, some questions
一些快速事实，一些问题
that we will look at today about the Islamic Golden Age.
我们今天要探讨的关于伊斯兰黄金时代的内容
The first major question is, while
第一个主要问题是，当欧洲处于黑暗时代时，
Europe was in its dark ages,
伊斯兰正踏上其黄金时代。
Islam was embarked on its Golden Age.
So the first question is, how did this happen?
那么第一个问题是，这一切是怎么发生的？
Why was there this divergence?
为什么会出现这种分化？
The second question we're going to look at is,
第二个问题我们要探讨的是，
what ended the Islamic Golden Age?
什么结束了伊斯兰的黄金时代？
Why would this period come to an end?
为什么这个时期会落幕？
The third question we're going to look at is, eventually,
第三个问题是，最终……
how did Christian Europe overtake the Muslim world?
基督教欧洲是如何超越穆斯林世界的？
So those are the three big questions we will look at.
于是这就是我们要探讨的三大问题。
We will look at that in today's class.
我们将在今天的课上来看看。
Some quick facts about Islam.
伊斯兰的快速概况。
It is the world's second largest religion.
它是世界第二大宗教。
Christianity has two billion people.
基督教有二十亿人。
Islam has one billion people.
伊斯兰有十亿人口。
They are divided into two major sects.
它们分为两大教派。
The Shia, which is based primarily in Iran,
什叶派主要分布在伊朗。
and the Sunni, which is everywhere else.
逊尼，分布在其它地方。
The light green are the Sunni people.
浅绿表示逊尼人。
And the dark green are the Sunni.
深绿表示逊尼人。
And the light green are the Shia people. And as you can see,
浅绿表示什叶派人。正如你所见，
Islam extends all across Africa,
伊斯兰遍布非洲、中东、中亚及印度。
the Middle East, and Central Asia and into India.
The most populous Muslim country in the world is actually Indonesia.
世界上人口最多的穆斯林国家实际上是印度尼西亚。
The Shia and the Sunni,
什叶派与逊尼派，
the only major difference is
唯一主要差别是
that the Shia believe that
什叶派认为
only a direct descendant of Muhammad's grandson,
只有穆罕默德孙子的直系后裔
Ali, can be the leader of the religion,
阿里才能成为宗教领袖
whereas the Sunni do not believe this.
而逊尼派则不这么认为。
Now, this is a religion of one billion people,
现在，这是一种拥有十亿人的宗教，
so there are many different belief systems,
因此有许多不同的信仰体系。
many different sects within this cosmology.
在这个宇宙观里有许多不同的教派。
But this is really the major difference between the Shia
但这才是什叶派之间的主要区别。
and the Sunni. So,
以及逊尼派。因此，
So, Muslim means to submit yourself to God.
于是，穆斯林就是全心投身于上帝。
To believe in God and
信仰上帝并
to submit yourself wholeheartedly to Him.
全心投身于他。
And Islam was founded by a man named Muhammad,
伊斯兰由一名叫穆罕默德的人创立，
who the Muslims consider the prophet of God,
他被穆斯林视为上帝的先知。
the final prophet. And Jesus was the penultimate prophet.
最后一位先知。耶稣是倒数第二位先知。
And the Muslim religion is based on this. And the legend is
穆斯林宗教以此为根基，传说亦如此。
that at age 40 Muhammad,
那时四十岁的穆罕默德，[48] 他是商人或贸易商，便有了异象。
who is a merchant or a trader, he has a vision.
who is a merchant or atrader, he has a vision.
He goes into a cave to meditate and
他进入山洞冥想并
the archangel Gabriel visits him and
大天使加百利来访他并
reveals to him certain visions that he has memorized.
向他展示他已记住的异象。
And these visions become the basis for the holy book of the Muslim tradition called the Koran.
这些异象成为穆斯林传统圣书《可兰经》的基础。
And Muhammad understands that Muhammad is a prophet.
穆罕默德明白自己是先知。
And he believes that his mission is to be a messenger of God
他相信自己的使命是上帝的使者。
and to reveal the truth of God to the pagan society in the Arabian world.
并向阿拉伯世界的异教社会揭示上帝的真理。
So, he's based in Mecca.
于是，他在麦加落脚。
And when he tries to reveal the truth,
当他尝试揭示真理时。
he is met with a lot of resistance.
他遇到了很多抵抗。
And eventually he's forced out of Mecca and he goes to Medina.
最终他被迫离开麦加，前往麦地。
This is called the Hijra in the Muslim tradition, the pilgrimage.
这被称为穆斯林传统中的希贾拉，即朝圣。
And when he goes to Medina, he goes to the holy book of the Koran. And
当他前往麦地，他便去读《可兰经》。并且
he becomes the leader of
他成为领袖
the warring factions within Medina,
战乱派系的领袖
primarily between the pagans, the Muslim tribes, and the Jewish tribes.
主要在异教徒、穆斯林部落与犹太部落之间。
So, there are three major factions.
于是有三大派系。
And at this point,
此时，
Muhammad creates what we call the Constitution of Medina,
穆罕默德制定了我们称之为麦地宪章的文件，并承诺给穆斯林传统中的每个人宗教自由。
which promises religious freedom to everyone
它为所有人提供宗教自由的保证。
within the Muslim tradition.
在穆斯林传统中，人人都享有宗教自由。
Okay? So, ever since the beginning,
好的？所以，自从一开始，
and this is very important, the religion of Islam was an open,
而且这点非常重要，伊斯兰教是一种开放、
tolerant, and inclusive religion.
宽容且包容的宗教。
And they have basically maintained this tradition for the next thousand years.
他们基本上在接下来的千年里保持了这一传统。
Okay? Eventually,
好吧？最终，
Islam will spread from the Arabian desert to all across the Middle East.
伊斯兰将从阿拉伯沙漠扩展至整个中东。
They will conquer the Persian Empire.
他们将征服波斯帝国。
And they will take at least half of the Byzantine Empire,
他们至少会占领拜占帝国的一半。
including the richest parts of the Byzantine Empire,
包括叙利亚和埃及等拜占帝国最富饶的地区。
which are Syria and Egypt.
其中叙利亚与埃及为拜占帝国最富饶的地区。
They will also take Jerusalem, where
他们还会占领耶路撒，那里他们将建造一座叫阿尔-阿克萨清真寺的建筑。
they will build something called the Al -Aqsaq Mosque.
And legend has it that
并且传说
Muhammad ascended to heaven from this place.
穆罕默德从此升天
Now, it's really important for us to remember about this place.
现在，记住这地方真的很重要。
The Al -Aqsaq Mosque is still there in Jerusalem.
阿尔-阿克萨清真寺仍在耶路撒。
And it is built on top of something called the Temple Mount.
并且它建在被称为圣殿山的地方之上。
Remember, in the year 70,
记住，公元70年，
the Romans burned down the second temple of the Jews,
罗马人焚毁了犹太人的第二座圣殿，是犹太信仰中最圣洁的地方。
the holiest site in the Jewish faith.
然后穆斯林们来了。
And then the Muslims came and
built the Al -Aqsaq Mosque on top of the Temple Mount.
在圣殿山之上建造了阿尔-阿克萨清真寺。
Now, this is a very strange thing to do.
现在，这件事很奇怪。
If the Muslim tradition is open,
若穆斯林传统是开放的，
inclusive, and tolerant, and
包容的，宽容的，且…
Jews are welcome into the tradition,
犹太人被纳入传统，受欢迎
why would you build a mosque on top of the Jewish holy site?
为什么要在犹太圣地之上建造清真寺？
That doesn't really make any sense.
这句话真没啥道理。
And quite honestly, this has been a mystery to everyone.
说实在，这件事一直是个谜。
No one has been able to figure this out, okay?
到现在还没人搞懂，行吗？
So we will today attempt to solve one of the great mysteries.
于是今天我们将尝试解开一个大谜题。
Why was the Al -Aqsaq Mosque built on top of the Jewish Temple Mount?
为什么阿尔-阿克萨清真寺建在犹太圣殿之上？
As I mentioned,
正如我所说，
the Arabs will expand from the desert of Arabia,
阿拉伯人将从阿拉伯沙漠扩张，并征服萨珊波斯帝国。
and they will conquer the Sassanian Persian Empire.
他们将占领拜占庭至少一半。
And they will take at least half of the Byzantines.
They will try to lay siege on Constantinople,
他们会尝试围攻君士坦丁堡，但记得我们讨论过拜占庭时，拜占庭帝国，君士坦丁堡被设计成一座不可攻破的要塞。
but remember that when we discussed the Byzantines, the Byzantine Empire,
Constantinople is designed as an impenetrable fortress.
他们会尝试围攻君士坦丁堡，但记得我们讨论过拜占庭时，拜占庭帝国，君士坦丁堡被设计成一座不可攻破的要塞。
So there will be two major sieges, and because
于是会有两次大围攻，且因为城墙和希腊火的缘故，
of the walls, and because of Greek fire,
他们将无法攻占城池。
they will be unable to take the city.
The spread of Islam was lightning fast.
伊斯兰的传播如闪电般迅速。
In less than 100 years, they spread from the desert of Arabia,
不到百年，他们从阿拉伯沙漠扩展开来，
really the poorest place in this entire region,
这整个地区最贫瘠的地方。
throughout most of the Middle East.
在中东大部分地区。
So the dark green is where they started, and the light green is
于是深绿表示他们起点，浅绿表示最终扩展范围。
where they eventually expanded to.
And remember, this process takes less than 100 years,
并且记住，这一过程不到百年，真是了不起。
which is remarkable. The Umayyad Caliphate was about 700.
乌马雅德哈里发国大约七百年。
So let's just compare the Umayyad Caliphate with other empires,
于是我们把乌马雅德哈里发国与其它帝国做个对比。
including the Tang. The Tang really is the height of Chinese civilization.
包括唐朝。唐朝真是中国文明的巅峰。
But as you can see, the Umayyad Caliphate
但正如你所见，乌马雅德哈里发国
really is the largest empire in the world at this time.
真是当时世界最大的帝国。
And eventually, they will also become the wealthiest empire at this time.
最终，他们也会成为当时最富有的帝国。
There are five pillars of Islam.
伊斯兰教有五根柱子。
It is an extremely simple
它非常简单。
and clear religion when
与基督教和犹太教相比，宗教很清晰。
compared with Christianity and Judaism.
宗教有五根柱子。
There are five pillars to the religion.
有五根柱子。
First of all, you have to believe that Allah, God,
首先，你要相信阿拉，真主，只有一位真主。
is the only God.
这与基督教和犹太教的信仰相似。
And this mirrors the Christian and the Jewish faith.
You are required to pray at least five times a day.
你每天至少要祷五次。
Facing the direction of Mecca.
面向麦加方向。
You must give money to the poor.
你要给穷人捐钱。
You must fast during the holy days.
你必须在圣日里斋戒。
And last thing is, you must make something called the Hajj,
最后一件事是，你要完成一次叫做朝觅的仪式。
which is a pilgrimage to the holy site in Mecca
这是一场前往麦加圣地的朝觅。
and perform rituals in Mecca.
在麦加完成仪式并进行礼拜。
This is something that all Muslims must do.
这是所有穆斯林都必须做的事。
And you will have the poorest Muslims.
你会遇到最贫穷的穆斯林。
They will save, their entire lives, just so that they can make this Hajj.
他们会把一生都奉献给这趟朝觅。
The Muslim people are probably the most devout,
穆斯林大概是你会遇到最虔诚、最虔信的人。
the most religious people you will meet.
他们是最虔诚、最虔信的人。
They take their religion very, very seriously.
他们把宗教当得非常、非常认真。
This is the Hajj in Mecca.
这就是麦加的朝觅。
And I was actually in Saudi Arabia, and I tried to go there.
我实际上在沙特阿拉伯，试着去那里。
And I was told, only Muslims can go.
我被告知，只有穆斯林才能去。
And so, as a train station,
于是，我像在火车站一样，
I was trying to buy a ticket to Mecca.
我正试着买去麦加的车票。
And they said, what's your Muslim name?
他们问，您的穆斯林名字是什么？
Well, I'm not Muslim. Well, you can't go then.
我说，我不是穆斯林。于是你们说，没办法去。
So, I was disappointed.
于是我失落了。
But it is a beautiful,
但它很美丽，
absolutely one of the most beautiful rituals
绝对是世界上最美丽的仪式之一，
in the world today.
目前的世界上。
Okay. So, to summarize the introduction,
好的。总结一下引言，
there are three major mysteries to the history of Islam
有三个关于伊斯兰历史的主要谜团，
that we still haven't really solved today.
我们至今仍未真正解开。
Okay, the first mystery is,
好的，第一个谜团是，
we know that they have something called the Constitution of Medina.
我们知道他们有一个叫做麦地那宪法的东西。
We also know that Jews, who are literate,
我们也知道犹太人，文盲的。
were part of the early movement of Islam.
它们是伊斯兰早期运动的一部分。
So, why do we have no early records for the first 100 years?
那么，为什么我们在前一百年没有早期记录？
What if the first 100 years of the movement?
如果早期运动的前一百年是怎样的呢？
That's very, very strange. Okay.
这很，十分奇怪。好的。
Another strange thing is,
另一个奇怪的事是，
why would the Muslims go to war against two major empires?
为什么穆斯林会对两个大帝国发动战争？
The Romans and the Persians. That's kind of suicidal.
罗马人和波斯人。那有点自杀的味道。
They didn't know they were going to win. So, why did they go to war?
他们不知道自己会赢。那为什么他们要去打仗？
Okay, that's the first mystery we'll solve today.
好了，这就是今天我们要解决的第一个谜题。
Second mystery is, remember I said
第二个谜题是，记得我说过
that the Shia and the Sunni
什叶派和逊尼派
have a major sectarian divide.
有一个重大的教派分裂。
The Shia believe that only the descendants of Muhammad's grandson Ali can be the caliph,
什叶派认为只有穆罕默德的孙子阿里后裔才能成为哈里发。
the leader of the Muslim people.
穆斯林人的领袖。
The Sunnis don't. So, why didn't Muhammad just name a successor
逊尼派没有。那穆罕默德为什么不直接指定继任者？
and avoid civil wars that will erupt after his death?
并避免他去世后爆发的内战？
The third question is,
第三个问题是，
why was Al -Aqsaq built on the site of the Temple Mount?
为什么阿尔-阿克萨被建在圣殿山的地点？
And this is still a problem today because
而这件事至今仍是个问题，因为…
a lot of conflict in the Middle East is driven by this problem
中东的许多冲突由此问题驱动
where the Jews want to rebuild the Temple, but
犹太人想重建圣殿
to do so, they would have to destroy the Al -Aqsaq Mosque,
为此，他们必须摧毁阿尔-阿克萨清真寺，
which is the third holiest site in the Islam world.
它是伊斯兰世界第三圣地。
So, this is a very important question that is still relevant to us today.
所以，这个问题非常重要，至今仍与我们相关。
So, we will also look at these three mysteries.
接下来我们也会探讨这三个谜题。
And again, no one knows the answers to any of these three questions,
又一次，没有人知道这三个问题的答案，
and no one will ever know because so much of historical record has been lost to us.
又一次，没有人会知道，因为大量历史记录已流失。
But I will try to provide you with an explanation,
但我会尝试给你一个解释，
okay, given my understanding of the Islamic world,
好了，按我对伊斯兰世界的理解，
which, by the way, is extremely limited, okay?
顺便说一句，我的了解非常有限，
So, please ask questions.
请提问吧。
Please challenge me.
请来挑战我。
I'm looking at you, Doug, okay?
我正看着你，Doug，好吗？
All right. All right.
好的。好的。
Okay. So, today's topic is the Islamic Golden Age.
好了。那么，今天的主题是伊斯兰的黄金时代。
So, let's just have a quick look at the Golden Age.
好了，让我们快速看看黄金时代。
At the height of Islamic influence,
在伊斯兰影响的巅峰时，
there were a few centers
有若干个中心
of incredible cultural creativity.
是极具文化创造力的城市。
One such site is Bukhara, Uzbekistan.
一个这样的地方是乌兹别克斯坦的布哈拉。
It's still there, guys. You can get on a plane like Doug did and visit it.
它仍然在那里，大家。你可以像道格一样乘飞机去参观。
It is an incredible city.
它是一座不可思议的城市。
I say that, not actually having visited it, but
我这么说是因为没亲自去过，但听道格说得很精彩。
I've heard terrific things from Doug.
你也可以上网看看视频。
And you can go online as well and look at videos.
And you can go online aswell and look at videos.
But it is an incredible city.
它是一座不可思议的城市。
And it shows you the immense creativity,
它展示了伊斯兰黄金时代的巨大创造力，
the artistic creativity of the Islamic Golden Age. But
艺术创造力。
the main cultural center of the
巴格达是伊斯兰黄金时代的主要文化中心，好的？
Islamic Golden Age is Baghdad, okay?
它现在不再那么美丽了。
It's not so beautiful now,
but back then it was really the center of the world.
但那时它真是世界的中心。
It's a round city and it's a new city.
它是一座圆形的新城。
This is a topographical map of the city.
这是城的地形图。
As you can see, it's surrounded by the Tigris and Euphrates, and it is a round city, okay?
如你所见，它被底格里斯河和幼发河环绕，是一座圆形城市，没错？
One of the few round cities of that time.
那时少有的圆形城市之一。
Baghdad was the capital of the Abbasids.
巴格达是阿拔斯王朝的首都。
And the Abbasid Caliphate, which started the Islamic Golden Age.
阿拔斯王朝是伊斯兰黄金时代的起点。
The Abbasid Caliphate is the successor to the Umayyad Empire,
阿拔斯王朝继承了倭马亚王朝。
okay? And this is where the Abbasid Caliphate was.
好的？这就是阿拔斯王朝的所在地。
And this is what Muslims consider the height of their civilization.
这就是穆斯林们认为其文明巅峰的地方。
The thing that's really important for us to understand about the Abbasid Empire is
关于阿拔斯王朝，最重要的是我们要理解的点是……
that not only were they influential in the Muslim world,
不仅在穆斯林世界中具有影响力，……
but they eventually would come to create the world that we live in today.
但他们最终会创造出我们今天所生活的世界。
Okay? So, when we think of globalization,
好了？所以，当我们想到全球化时，
we think of this as a recent phenomenon.
我们把它视为一种最近的现象。
But, look at the trade route that the Abbasid Caliphate would create
但，看看阿拔斯哈里发所开辟的贸易路线
over its 300 -400 year history.
在其300-400年的历史中。
It connects the entire world.
它连接了整个世界。
Okay? Um,
好了？嗯，
as I mentioned last semester,
正如我上学期所说，
globalization has always existed to a certain extent
全球化在世界历史中一直以一定程度存在。
in world history.
But the Abbasids, the Muslim religion,
但阿拔斯王朝，穆斯林宗教，
would take these existing networks and
将把这些已有的网络
make them a lot richer, a lot more dense, and a lot faster.
让它们更富饶、更密集、更迅速。
Okay? So, um, you may not know this,
好了？所以，嗯，你可能不知道这件事。
but the Abbasids traded heavily with the Tang
但阿拔斯王朝与唐朝和宋朝有大量贸易。
and the Song dynasties.
In fact, it is the Abbasids who
实际上，正是阿拔斯王朝
would initiate something called the Maritime Silk Road.
他们将发起一项被称为海上丝绸之路的事业
The Overland Silk Road has existed for a long time,
陆上丝绸之路已存在很久，
but it is the Abbasids who will eventually create the Maritime Silk Road.
但最终是阿拔斯王朝创造了海上丝绸之路。
And it will bring China into the world
这将把中国带入世界。
to a greater extent than ever before.
比以前更大程度。
Okay? So, um, this is just a quick summary.
好的？所以，这只是一个快速总结。
So, let's get into trade. Um,
好了，开始谈贸易。
the main center for cultural production
穆斯林世界的文化生产中心是被称为“智慧之屋”的地方。
in the Muslim world is something called the House of Wisdom.
它的模型是……
And its model, um,
its model is the Library of Alexandria.
它的模型是亚历山大图书馆。
Okay? Remember last semester we discussed the Library of Alexandria in Egypt.
好的？记得上学期我们讨论过埃及的亚历山大图书馆。
And its mission was to be the first university to take
它的使命是成为第一所大学，收集……
all! Hellenistic knowledge and
全！希腊知识与文化，
culture and systemize it for, um,
并将其系统化，
uh, dissemination. Okay?
用于传播。
And the House of Wisdom, uh, was doing the same thing,
并且智慧之屋也在做同样的事，
where it would take all knowledge
它会收集伊斯兰世界内的所有知识
and culture within the Islamic world
以及文化
and outside the Islamic world and systemize
并在伊斯兰世界之外进行系统化
and center that, center it for mass dissemination.
并将其中心化，便于大众传播
Okay? So,
好的？
um, the things that they were doing were, they were, they were taking,
嗯，他们正在做的事是，他们正在做的事是，他们正在取……
they were taking Hindu numerals, okay, so 0, 1, 2, 3, we still use them today.
他们取了印度数字，好的，所以0、1、2、3，我们今天仍在使用它们。
They took them from India, and again, they standardized it and
他们从印度取来，再次，他们把它们标准化。
disseminated this knowledge.
传播了这知识。
They took works from Aristotle and Plato,
他们把亚里士多德和柏拉图的作品带来，
translated into Arabic and
翻译成阿拉伯语
Persian, and then disseminated it.
波斯语，然后传播了它。
Um, they,
嗯，他们，
the main contribution of the Islamic Golden Age to world culture is in actually mathematics.
伊斯兰黄金时代对世界文化的主要贡献实际上是数学。
Okay? So they took all the math,
好的？于是他们把所有的数学……
um, in the Greek world and in the Persian world
嗯，在希腊世界和波斯世界……
and in, in the Hindu world, and then
以及在印度世界……
they would systemize it and then build on top of it.
他们会把它系统化，然后在此基础上再建造。
Okay? Um,
好？ 嗯，
this is a rendition of the House of Wisdom.
这是一种《智慧之屋》的演绎。
This is where the three major creative civilizations would meet
这就是三大创作文明相会的地方
and exchange ideas, right?
并且互相交流想法，对吧？
The Greeks, the Jews, and the Persians.
希腊、犹太和波斯
They would also take ideas from the Indian tradition and the Chinese tradition as well.
他们还会从印度传统和中国传统中汲取思想。
Um, the major literature or literary work
嗯，主要的文学作品是……
that we still have today from the Islamic Golden Age is the Arabian Nights,
我们今天仍然拥有的伊斯兰黄金时代的文学作品是《一千零一夜》
okay? Um, scholars have looked at this very closely
好的？嗯，学者们已经非常仔细地研究过这件事
and most scholars believe that these stories are actually from India.
并且大多学者认为这些故事其实来自印度
Also, what's important for us to understand, is that
另外，对我们理解来说重要的是
at that, at the time this was translated,
在那时，那段文字被翻译时，
it was actually not that popular within the Muslim world.
那时在穆斯林世界里并不算很流行。
Poetry, philosophy,
诗歌、哲学、
mathematics, science were considered the high arts.
数学、科学被视为高等艺术。
This was considered low arts.
这被视为低等艺术。
what we have today is that the Europeans would discover this
今天我们所拥有的是，欧洲人将会发现它。
centuries after the Islamic Golden Age
几百年后，伊斯兰黄金时代
and they fell in love with these stories and that's why we still have them today.
他们沉醉于这些故事，这也是我们今天仍然拥有它们的原因
Um, and Disney movies are based on this.
呃，迪士尼电影就是基于此
So, um, we have a lot of history on this as well.
于是，呃，我们也有很多关于这方面的历史。
Okay, so let's look at the, some of the major thinkers
好了，让我们看看伊斯兰黄金时代的一些主要思想家和哲学家。
and philosophers of the Islamic Golden Age.
接下来是这些主要思想家和哲学家。
So, at this time in world history, we don't differentiate between philosophers,
于是，在世界历史的这个时期，我们不区分哲学家、诗人、科学家、数学家，嗯？
poets, uh, scientists, mathematicians, okay?
所有知识分子都在这些不同领域里工作，嗯？
All intellectuals engage in all these different fields, okay?
好了，所有知识分子都在这些不同领域里工作，嗯？
So, the one most famous is Rumi, who is Persian.
于是，最著名的是鲁米，他是波斯人。
A poet, a mystic, a philosopher.
一位诗人，一位神秘者，一位哲学家。
Ibn Sina is probably the most famous
伊本·西纳大概是最著名的。
intellectual of the Islamic Golden Age.
伊斯兰黄金时代的知识分子。
Um, his books,
嗯，他的书，
his works were admired in Europe.
他的作品在欧洲受到赞赏。
Okay? So, the Islamic, the Islamic philosophy,
好的？于是，伊斯兰的伊斯兰哲学，
um, was being exported to Europe
嗯，正被出口到欧洲
where, where they would have a major influence on many of Europe's major thinkers.
在那里，它们将对欧洲许多重要思想家产生重大影响。
You may have heard a man named Leonardo Fibonacci.
你可能听说过一位叫莱昂纳多·斐波那奇的人。
You should have heard of him in math class.
你应该在数学课上听说过他。
Well, well, at this particular time in history,
好吧，在这段历史的特定时期，
he was going to Baghdad to study from the leading mathematicians of this time
他前往巴格达，向当时的顶尖数学家学习
and taking their ideas and, um, importing
并把他们的思想……导入欧洲
them all back to Europe.
随后把这些全部带回欧洲
Okay? So, this is Ibn Sina, uh,
好的？所以，这位是伊本·西那，呃，
and the Latin name is Avicenna.
拉丁名是阿维森纳。
Um, Ibn Ruzza, Averroes,
嗯，伊本·鲁扎，阿维罗斯。
is also, um,
它也是，呃，
a major intellectual at this time.
当时的主要知识分子之一。
Just to show you how influential these two were in Europe,
仅仅是为了让你知道这两位在欧洲的影响力。
let's look at Dante's Divine Comedy.
让我们来看看但丁的《神曲》。
So, Dante is in, uh,
于是，但丁在，呃，
hell, and there in limbo,
在地狱里，在灵魂的等待之地。
he's meeting the most influential,
他正在会见最有影响力的，
the greatest philosophers in human history who have influenced European history.
人类历史上最伟大的哲学家，他们影响了欧洲历史。
Okay? Okay?
好的？好的？
Okay? Okay? Okay?
好的？好的？好的？
Okay? Okay?
Okay? Okay? Okay?
好的吗？好的吗？好的吗？
Okay? Okay? Okay? Okay?
好的吗？好的吗？好的吗？好的吗？
This is something you do not learn in school usually.
这是一件平时学校里不学的事。
But without Islam, you can make the argument that Europe could not have modernized.
但若没有伊斯兰，你可以说欧洲没能现代化。
And later on, I'll explain why that's the case.
随后我会解释原因。
Omar Khayyam is also another famous
奥马尔·哈亚姆也是另一位著名人物。
intellectual, poet, philosopher.
知识分子、诗人、哲学家。
This man, Musa al -Hazami,
这位人，穆萨·阿尔-哈扎米，
is considered the father of modern -day algebra.
被认为是现代代数之父。
His Latin name is algorithm.
他的拉丁名是algorithm。
And if this sounds familiar,
如果这听起来熟悉，
it's because his name will give us the modern English word algorithm.
因为他的名字给了我们现代英语单词algorithm。
Both algebra and algorithm were originally Arabic words. So
两者——代数与算法——最初是阿拉伯语词。于是……
most of the math you're studying in school actually originated during the Islamic golden age.
你在学校学的数学大多来自伊斯兰黄金时代。
This name is al -Hazan, and he invented algebra.
此名为阿尔-哈扎姆，他发明代数。
He invented physics, basically, optics. Again, extremely influential.
他发明物理，基本上是光学。再次，极具影响力。
And again, these ideas will be imported back to Europe
再一次，这些思想会被引进欧洲
and they will become the basis of the Renaissance.
并成为文艺复兴的基础。
Al -Zahari is the father of surgery.
阿尔-扎哈里是外科之父。
At this time in world history,
此时世界历史上，
the very best hospitals are in the Islamic world, by far.
最好的医院无疑在伊斯兰世界。
This is the first 24 -hour hospital in Baghdad.
这是巴格达第一家24小时医院。
What's also amazing about these hospitals is
这些医院的另一个惊人之处是
that if you are poor and cannot pay,
如果你是贫困且无力支付
you could receive medical treatment for free.
你可以免费接受医疗治疗。
That was just part of the faith.
那只是信仰的一部分。
All poor were treated with great charity and kindness
所有贫困者都以大慈善和善意得到治疗。
during the Islamic golden age.
在伊斯兰黄金时代期间。
This is Al -Khawar William.
这是阿尔-卡瓦尔·威廉。
Again, guys, I don't speak Arabic.
再说一次，我不说阿拉伯语。
I'm probably butchering the name.
我大概在说名字了。
But it was found in 859 in Fes, Morocco, this is important
它成立于859年，位于摩洛哥的菲斯，这点很重要。
because this is actually the first degree -granting university in the whole world.
这实际上是全世界第一所授予学位的大学。
It's still there, guys. This is the oldest university in the world.
它仍然在，大家。它是世界上最古老的大学。
What's also amazing is it was founded by a woman
更令人惊讶的是，它是由一位女性创办的。
who inherited a fortune from her father,
她从父亲那里继承了一笔财富。
and she spent all her money on building this university.
她把所有的钱都投入建造这所大学。
All right? If you ever get a chance to go to Fes,
好了？如果你有机会去菲斯，
it is the most amazing city in the world.
那是世界上最令人惊叹的城市。
Morocco is an amazing country as well.
摩洛哥也是个很棒的国家。
Okay, so 1258,
好了，1258年，
the Islamic golden age officially came to an end, or that's what scholars believe.
伊斯兰黄金时代正式结束，或者说是学者们的看法。
And the reason why is on 1258, the Mongols will sack Baghdad
于是，1258年，成吉尔人要攻占巴格达，原因就在这里。
and they will burn all the books, okay?
他们会把所有书都烧掉，没错。
Or that's what the legend tells us.
或者说这就是传说的内容。
Baghdad had a thriving bookstore.
巴格达拥有繁荣的书店。
It was a very popular bookstore. And this was unique in the world.
它是一家非常受欢迎的书店，这在世界上独一无二。
Intellectuals, or the elite, they spent a lot of their resources on buying books.
知识分子，或称作精英，他们把大量资源投入买书。
And they imported paper from China.
他们从中国进口纸张。
They learned how to make paper from China.
他们学会了中国的造纸技艺。
So books were extremely popular within Baghdad,
于是书籍在巴格达极为流行。
especially among the elite.
尤其在精英中。
As well, because of the Quran,
同样，因为《可兰经》……
it was necessary for the elite to be literate.
因此精英必须识字。
It was the mandate of you to be literate.
它是你们必须识字的使命。
And the Quran will also standardize Arabic and
《可兰经》也将统一阿拉伯语，并使其成为整个穆斯林世界的官方语言。
make it the official language of the entire Muslim world.
Okay? But
好的？但
just because the Islamic golden age ended does not mean
仅仅因为伊斯兰黄金时代结束，并不意味着…
that creating stopped in the Muslim world.
…在穆斯林世界里创造就停止了。
This is Ibn Khaldun, and he is considered the father,
这是伊本·哈伦，他被认为是社会科学之父，好吗？
the father of social science, okay?
经济学，定量史学，…
Economics, quantitative history,
politics.
政治。
This man invented a lot of these disciplines.
这位先生发明了许多这些学科。
He is most famous for his idea of asabiyah,
他最著名的是他的阿萨比亚概念。
which just means social cohesion.
这只是指社会凝聚力。
So he was actually the first
于是他实际上是第一个
to systematically think about Quran history.
系统性地思考古兰经历史的人。
Why do civilization, why do civilizations rise and why do they decline?
文明为何兴起，何以衰落？
And his conclusion is that
他的结论是：
the borderlands are able to conquer empires
边疆能征服帝国。
because the borderlands,
因为边疆，
the people there, have asabiyah, which just means that they are more egalitarian,
那里的人民有阿萨比亚，正是指他们更平等，
more free, more cohesive as a culture.
更自由，更有文化凝聚力。
Whereas the empire,
而帝国，
because it's so big, it loses a lot of cohesion.
因为它很大，失去不少凝聚力。
Okay? And
好的？
again, Ibn Khaldun is a major inspiration for the history
再次，伊本·哈伦是我尝试的历史的主要灵感。
that I try as well.
从1300年到1700年。
From 1300 to 1700,
the world will be dominated by three major empires.
世界将由三大帝国主导。
The Ottomans, the Safayids in Iran, and the Mughals in India.
奥斯曼帝国、伊朗的萨法王朝和印度的莫卧尔王朝。
They are collectively known as the gun power empires.
它们合称为火枪王国。
So what's amazing is,
于是令人惊奇的是，
since its inception about 622,
自从大约622年起，
up until the year 1700,
一直到1700年。
the Islamic religion dominate the world.
伊斯兰宗教主导世界。
And so the question for us is, why was that the case?
于是我们要问的就是，为什么会出现这种情况？
How did Islam overtake Europe and overtake Christianity?
伊斯兰是如何先占领欧洲又先占领基督教的？
Okay? That is the mystery and question for us today that we will look at.
好的？这就是今天我们要探讨的谜团与问题。
Okay. So let's go back to the three mysteries that
好的。接下来我们回到之前提到的三个谜团。
I introduced earlier.
Why do we have no written records?
为什么我们没有书面记录？
Even though we know that the people within the movement, Jews and Christians,
即使我们知道运动中的人们，犹太人和基督徒，懂得读写。
knew how to read and write.
knew how to readand write.
Okay? That's the first question. Second question is,
好的？那是第一个问题。第二个问题是，
why didn't Muhammad name a successor?
为什么穆罕默德没有指定继任者？
The third question is,
第三个问题是，
why was the Al -Qasr mosque built on top of the Temple Mount?
为什么阿尔-卡斯尔清真寺建在圣殿山顶？
Okay? So,
好的吗？那么，
this is a paradox because Jews were an extremely important part of the Muslim world.
这是一种矛盾，因为犹太人是穆斯林世界极其重要的一部分。
They were an important part of that early movement.
它们是那个早期运动的重要组成部分。
Right? So why would you offend the Jews like this?
对吧？那为什么要这样冒犯犹太人？
Alright. Okay.
好的。好吧。
To understand what happened, okay, let's go back in time.
要了解发生了什么，先回到过去。
And we know that in 622,
我们知道在622年，
Muhammad goes to Medina and
穆罕默德去麦地那。
that's what starts the Islamic movement.
那就是伊斯兰运动的起点。
But let's just go over to Jerusalem and figure out what's happening there.
我们先去耶路撒冷，看看那里的情况。
And once we do that,
完成后就能搞清楚那里的事了。
then we're able to figure out what's going on in that world.
然后我们就能搞清楚那世界的情况了。
It turns out that in 622,
结果是，在622年，
there's a major war going on between the two major powers at this time.
当时两大势力之间正爆发一场大规模战争。
The Persians and the Byzantines.
波斯人和拜占庭人。
And it is a deadly war
而且这是一场致命的战争
that is engulfing the entire Middle East.
正席卷整个中东。
Okay? So this is from Wikipedia.
好的？这来自维基百科。
Alright? Now, guys,
好的？现在，大家，
never trust Wikipedia as a historical source.
先别把维基百科当作史料。
But it's useful for us.
但这对我们很有用。
To understand what contemporary historians think.
以便了解当代史学家们的看法。
Okay? So this is from Wikipedia.
好吧？这来自维基百科。
The Jews have aligned themselves with the Persians.
犹太人已与波斯人结盟。
Why? Because, first of all,
为什么？因为，首先，
the Romans controlled Jerusalem.
罗马人控制了耶路撒城。
And in the year 70,
[460] 于是公元70年，
the Romans burned down their temple.
[461] 罗马人焚毁了他们的圣殿。
And in the year 135,
[462] 公元135年，
the Romans expelled the Jews from Jerusalem,
罗马人把犹太人驱逐出耶路撒城，他们的圣城。
their holy city. So ever since then, the Jews,
自此以后，犹太人，显然想报仇，
obviously they want revenge, but
但……
they also want to return to their holy city and
他们也想回到自己的圣城并重建圣殿。
rebuild the temple.
并且与波斯人一起，他们把这视为一次机会。
And with the Persians, they saw this as an opportunity.
And with the Persians, theysaw this as an opportunity.
Because historically, the Persians and the Jews have gone along very well.
因为从历史上看，波斯人和犹太人合作得很顺利。
Okay? So, the Jews helped the Persians
好吧？于是犹太人帮助波斯人夺取耶路撒城并驱逐拜占廷。
take Jerusalem and push out the Byzantines.
随后拜占廷在赫拉克里乌斯皇帝的统领下，重新夺回耶路撒城。
When that happens,
当那件事发生时，
the Christians in Jerusalem, they revolt,
耶路撒城的基督徒起义，
and they force out the Jews.
把犹太人赶走。
And then the Byzantines, under the emperor Heraclius,
于是拜占廷在赫拉克里乌斯皇帝的统领下，
they return to Jerusalem
他们回到耶路撒城
in the first crusade.
在第一次十字军中
Okay? This is the beginning of the idea of crusade.
好的？这就是十字军概念的起点。
And they retake the city.
他们重新夺回城池。
And then what they do is,
随后他们所做的事是，
they expel the Jews from Jerusalem, obviously.
他们把犹太人驱逐出耶路撒城，显而易见。
But then, they start to
随后他们开始……
kill a lot of Jews. Okay?
又杀了不少犹太人。
And they force these Jews outside of Jerusalem.
他们把这些犹太人赶出耶路撒城。
So, now,
于是，现在，
these Jews have nowhere to go.
这些犹太人无处可去。
But, there's something called the of Medina in Arabia.
但，阿拉伯有个叫麦地那的地方。
Right? There is a prophet,
对吧？那里有先知。
Mohammed, who is promising religious tolerance for all.
穆罕默德，承诺为所有人提供宗教宽容。
All can practice their faith in peace.
大家都能在和平中实践自己的信仰。
Right? So it makes sense for a lot of these Jews, not all of them,
对吧？所以很多犹太人（不一定全部）会觉得加入这个早期运动很自然。
but a lot of them, to join this early movement.
于是很多犹太人（不一定全部）会觉得加入这个早期运动很自然。
What's important for us to understand is that, at this point, Islam,
对我们来说重要的是，到了这一步，伊斯兰、穆斯林并不是一种独立的宗教。
Muslim, is not a distinct religion.
Muslim, is not adistinct religion.
Okay? All these people are called believers.
这些人都被称为信徒。
Because Mohammed sees himself as the final messenger of God.
因为穆罕默德把自己视为上帝的最后使者。
Okay? Abraham was the first.
好的？亚伯拉罕是第一个。
Then you had Moses. Then you have Jesus.
然后你有摩西。接着你有耶稣。
And now, Mohammed is the very last.
现在，穆罕默德是最后的。
So all these three different traditions,
于是这三种不同的传统，
the Christian tradition, the Jewish tradition, and
基督教传统、犹太教传统和
the Islam tradition, in the beginning, were all just one religion.
伊斯兰传统在起初，都是同一宗教。
One idea. Which is to bring God to earth.
一个理念，便是把神带到人间。
And make everyone understand that God is the true God.
让众人明白神才是唯一真神。
Okay? To create monotheism on earth.
好的？在地上创立一神论。
That's the origin of this new religion of Islam.
这就是伊斯兰新宗教的起源。
Okay? And this is the constitutional religion.
好的？这就是宪法宗教。
The constitutional religion of Medina. Which is in the Quran.
麦地的宪法宗教。它在《可兰经》中出现。
And which we know to be historically true.
我们知道它在历史上是真实的。
Maybe not the wording. Okay?
也许不是那句词。
But we know that this existed. And
但我们知道它确实存在。并且
these people were called believers.
这些人被称为信徒。
And also, this would also include people who believed in Zoroastrianism.
而且，这其中也包括信奉祆教的人。
Okay? Because Zoroastrianism was also a monotheistic religion.
好的？因为祆教也是一神论宗教。
So, it was, so
所以，它是，所以……
the constitutional of Medina was an attempt to
麦地的宪法是一次尝试……
unite all monotheistic religions into one system.
统一所有一神论宗教为一体系。
And this was a single tradition that fought for God.
这是一种为神而战的单一传统。
Okay? Also, what's really important for us to understand is,
好了？我们真正需要理解的关键是，
not only is there all this persecution going on against Jews,
不只是犹太人受迫害，还有基督徒和祆教也在受迫害。
and against Christians, and against Zoroastrians.
好吧？但也……
Okay? But also,
this is a apocalyptic stage.
这是一个启示阶段。
Age. Where
时代。在哪儿
all three traditions believe this was literally the end of the world.
三大传统都认为这是真正的世界末日。
If you were Jewish, you believe in a final battle called Argamanon,
如果你是犹太人，你会相信有一场叫阿尔加曼的最终之战，
between the Messiah, who would lead you, and
在这场战斗中，弥赛亚将带领你们，
against two enemies called Gog and Magog.
并且与两敌——戈格与玛戈格——交战。
Okay? Guess what?
好的？猜猜是什么？
The Persians and the Romans were fighting each other.
波斯人和罗马人互相交战。
So you could easily interpret this to mean the Persians
于是你可以很容易地把它解释成波斯人…
and the Romans were the Gog and Magog enemy.
以及罗马人是戈格与玛戈格的敌人。
In new tradition, this would be the final battle.
在新的传统里，这将是最终之战。
This is when Jerusalem is most threatened.
此时耶路撒被最严重威胁。
Well, the Romans, the Byzantines, just took your city and mastered your people.
好吧，罗马人、拜占庭人刚刚占领了你的城市并掌控了你的人。
So in a Jewish tradition, this is the end of days.
于是，在犹太传统里，这就是末日。
This is the final battle. And
这就是最终之战。
the Messiah would emerge to lead you to final victory.
弥赛亚将出现，带领你们取得最终胜利。
That person, a lot of Jews could interpret to be Muhammad.
这人，许多犹太人可解作穆罕默德。
Okay? So for the Jews, this is the end of days.
好吧，于是犹太人认为这就是末日。
But for Christians, okay,
但对基督徒来说，好吧，他们也认为这是末日，因为有最终之战在先后基督徒与先后基督徒之间。
they also believe this is the end of days because
there were final battles between the Antichrist
但对基督徒来说，好吧，他们也认为这是末日，因为有最终之战在先后基督徒与先后基督徒之间。
and the Messiah.
和弥赛亚。
Okay? The Antichrist is obviously Heracles,
好吧？后期基督徒显然是赫拉克勒斯，
who is the emperor of the Byzantines,
他是拜占庭帝国的皇帝。
who'd been persecuting Christians for a long time.
他曾长期迫害基督徒。
Remember, the official religion of the Byzantines is the Holy Trinity.
记住，拜占庭人的官方宗教是圣三位一体。
But most Christians didn't believe in the Holy Trinity.
但大多数基督徒并未信奉圣三位一体。
They were persecuted for their refusal to believe in the Holy Trinity.
他们因不信圣三位一体而受迫害。
Okay? So for Christians, this is also the final battle.
好吧？所以对基督徒来说，这也是最后的战斗。
Zoroastrians believe in a final battle between good and evil.
祆教认为善恶之间会有一场终极之战。
Okay? So this is an apocalyptic age
好吧？这就是一个启示时代
where everyone believes this is it, the final battle.
在这个时代，人人都认为这就是终极之战。
Muhammad is saying to everyone, guys,
穆罕默德对大家说，伙计们，
we're all one people, united by God,
我们都是同一民族，由上帝团结，我们来此为他而战。
and we are here to fight for him.
好吧？这对人们很有吸引力。
Okay? And this is very appealing for people.
Okay? And this is veryappealing for people.
So the best evidence for my argument is actually the Quran.
所以我论点的最佳证据就是《可兰经》。”
Okay? So again, we don't have any written records of Muhammad.
好吧？所以我们再次没有穆罕默德的书面记录。”
But what we do believe is the Quran,
但我们所相信的就是《可兰经》。”
it is a collection of
它是一系列
many of Muhammad's original sayings
许多穆罕默德原话
that have been redacted over time.
被后世删改的
Okay? So
好吧？所以
let's look at some passages from the
让我们看看《可兰经》中的一些段落
Quran to better understand how Muhammad was thinking
以更好地理解穆罕默德的思考
and what he was preaching to the Christians, the Jews, and the Zoroastrians.
并且他向基督徒、犹太人和祆教徒所传的内容。
All right. All people of the book,
好的。书中所有人，
by this he means both the Christians and the Jews.
他指的是基督徒和犹太人。
Okay? Why do you argue about Abraham when
好吧？为什么你要争论亚伯拉罕？
the Torah and the Gospel were not revealed until after him?
因为《托拉》和《福音》在他之后才被启示？
Will you not reason? Okay?
你会不会推理吗？好吧？
So he's saying, why are we arguing about Scripture?
于是他在说，为什么我们要争论经书？
Why are we arguing about belief when we all acknowledge
我们为什么要争论信仰？我们都承认亚伯拉罕是我们的祖先。
that Abraham is our forefather?
Okay? And Abraham came before the Bible, he came before the Old Testament and the New Testament.
好吧？亚伯拉罕在圣经之前，他在旧约和新约之前。
So what's the argument? Here you are,
那么论点是什么？你现在说的是……
you argue about things you know, but why do you argue about things you do not know?
你会讨论你知道的事，但为什么还要讨论你不知道的事？
Allah knows and you do not know.
阿拉知道，而你不知道。
Abraham was neither a Jew nor a Christian,
亚伯拉罕既不是犹太人也不是基督徒，但他是独一神的信徒，亦即穆斯林。
but he was a monotheist, a Muslim.
Okay? So this is what Muhammad is saying.
好吧？这就是穆罕默德的说法。
A Muslim is someone who
穆斯林是指……
believes in God as the only true God,
相信唯一真神的那个人。
and that includes Jews and Christians.
包括犹太人和基督徒。
And he was not of the polytheists. Okay?
他不是多神论者。好吧？
Let's also look at Muhammad responding to the Christian tradition.
再看穆罕默德对基督徒传统的回应。
Remember, in the Christian tradition,
记住，在基督徒传统里，
a lot of conflict arises from a debate over the nature of Jesus
很多冲突来自于关于耶稣本性与他与上帝关系的争论。
and his relationship with God.
Okay? And what Muhammad is saying is, guys, the idea of Jesus makes no sense.
好的？穆罕默德说的是，大家，耶稣的概念没道理。
Jesus cannot be God.
耶稣不可能是上帝。
Jesus, at best, can only be a messenger of God, just like me.
耶稣，最起码是上帝的使者，跟我一样。
And the idea that Jesus is God makes no sense.
耶稣是上帝的概念没道理。
Jesus is a human, just like me.
耶稣是人，跟我一样。
God is God. He would not represent himself through a human.
上帝是上帝，他不会用人来代表自己。
Okay? And so let's look at what he says.
好的？那我们来看看他说了什么。
They disbelieved those who say, Allah is the Messiah, the son of Mary.
他们不信那些说阿拉是弥撒、玛丽之子的。
But the Messiah himself said, the Messiah is Jesus, right?
但弥撒自己说弥撒就是耶稣，对吧？
O children of Israel, worship Allah, my Lord and your Lord.
各位以色列子民，敬拜阿拉，我的主，也是你们的主。
He's making a clear distinction. God is my God.
他做了明确的区分。上帝是我的上帝。
I'm not God. I'm not his son.
我不是上帝，我也不是他的儿子。
He is God. Whoever associates others with Allah,
他是上帝。谁把其他人和阿拉合一，
Allah has forbidden him paradise, and his dwelling is a fire.
阿拉已把他禁入天堂，他的住处是火焰。
The wrongdoers have no saviors.
作恶者无救主。
All right? If you believe that Jesus is God,
一切都好？如果你认为耶稣是上帝，
you are committing heresy against the true God.
你就是在对真上帝犯异端。
There can only be one God. There can't be two gods together.
上帝只有一位，不能有两位。
They disbelieved those who say, Allah is a third of three.
他们不信那些说阿拉是三者之一的人。
But there is no deity except the one God.
但除了唯一的上帝，别无神。
If they do not refrain from what they say,
若他们不改口说法，
a painful torment will befall those among them who disbelieve.
对他们中不信者将降临痛苦的折磨。
So what he's saying, this is very important, is that Muhammad is saying,
所以他所说的，这点很重要，就是穆罕默德在说，
the Holy Trinity, the idea is just nonsense.
圣三位一体，那个想法就是胡说八道。
They disbelieve those who say, Allah is the third of three.
他们不信那些说阿拉是三者之一的人。
Allah cannot be a fraction of anything.
阿拉不可能是任何东西的分数。
He is the one and only.
他是唯一的。
Okay? Now, in our time,
好的？现在，在我们这个时代，
when we hear this,
当我们听到这个时，
we don't really have emotional reaction.
我们并没有真正的情绪反应。
But, place yourself back in their time.
但，回到他们的时代再想一想。
The year 622. Most Christians are being persecuted
公元622年，基督徒正被迫害。
for refusing to accept the Holy Trinity as scripture.
因拒绝把圣三位一体视为经书。
Because it makes no sense.
因为这毫无道理。
We discussed this in class.
我们在课堂上讨论过这个。
Okay? And now, but,
好的？现在，嗯，
if you say it makes no sense, you could be killed.
如果你说这毫无道理，你就可能被杀死。
Okay? You'll be persecuted for sure.
好？你一定会被迫害。
And now, Muhammad is saying,
现在，穆罕默德说，
you guys, you guys were right all along.
你们，早就对了。
You should have believed in yourself all along.
你们早就应该相信自己。
You were right all along. Okay?
你们早就对了。
So let's use an analogy. Let's just say, for example,
于是我们用个类比。比如说，
like the world government. Okay?
像是世界政府。好？
We have a world government. And for whatever reason, the world government tells us, the sky is red.
我们有个世界政府。无论何因，世界政府会告诉我们，天空是红色。
And you're like, wait a minute.
于是你说，等一下。
I know blue and I know red.
我知道蓝色，也知道红色。
And the sky is blue. But if you say,
天空是蓝色的。
the sky is blue, you will be put in jail.
天空是蓝色的，你会被关进监狱。
You are not allowed to say, hey, the sky is blue.
你不可以说，嘿，天空是蓝色的。
And then you have people, teachers like me, telling you,
然后你会有像我这样的老师告诉你，
the reason why you believe the sky is blue
天空是蓝色的原因是你的眼睛在说谎。
and not red is your eyes lie to you.
你无法相信自己。
You cannot trust yourself.
You cannot trustyourself.
You, your eyes are defective.
你，眼睛有缺陷。
That's a problem with human beings.
这就是人类的一个问题。
We can't trust what we see.
我们无法信任所见。
Okay? And you have to go through life believing the sky is red,
好的？然后你得在生活里相信天空是红色的，即使你心里知道它是蓝色的。
even though you know in your heart it's blue.
然后有一天，像老师一样的人在课堂上对你说：…】
But then one day, someone like a teacher says to you in class,
}
actually guys, we've been lying to you all along.
其实，伙计们，我们一直在对你们说谎。
The sky is blue. Imagine your sense of relief
天空是蓝色的。想象一下你的释然感、赋能感和解放感。
and empowerment and liberation
and empowermentand liberation
when someone of authority actually tells you what you've always believed.
当权威之人真正告诉你你一直相信的事时。
Okay? That's what Mohammed is doing.
好？这就是穆罕默德在做的事。
Mohammed is confirming to everyone that
穆罕默德向大家确认……
what they believed, what they knew about God was right all along.
他们所信的，关于上帝的所知，始终都正确。
Okay. So,
好的。那么，
Mohammed's final message to the people is,
穆罕默德给人们的最后信息是，
God is God and only God and he is everywhere.
神是神，只有神，他无处不在。
And you can see him.
你可以看到他。
You can touch him because he's everywhere.
你可以触摸他，因为他无处不在。
And as such, you can feel him and he can be inside of you.
于是你可以感受到他，他也能在你内部出现。
Okay? And so
好吗？于是如此。
this idea will actually occupy most of the Quran.
这个想法实际上会占据《古兰经》大部分。
And this is what he says, We believe, with him are the keys of the unseen.
于是他说：我们信仰，他与我们同在，掌握无形之钥匙。
None knows him except he.
唯有他自己知道他。
And he knows everything on land and in the sea.
他知晓陆权与海权的一切。
Not a leaf falls, but he knows it.
叶子落下，必知其形。
And there is not a single grain in the darkness of earth,
地暗无粒，亦无湿干，皆在清晰记录中。
nor is there anything wet or dry, but is in the clear record.
All right? God is everywhere.
好的？上帝无处不在。
You can see and touch him in everything.
你可以在万物中看到并触摸他。
Okay? And so in other words, what's happening is that
好的？换句话说，正在发生的事是……
Islam is really the first
伊斯兰真的是第一种现代意义上的一神论宗教。
monotheistic religion in the modern sense.
好的？当你想到一神论时，……
Okay? When you think of monotheism,
we actually think of the Islamic version of monotheism.
我们实际上想到的是伊斯兰版的一神论。
All right. So what's the power of Islam?
好吧。那么伊斯兰的力量是什么？
And I want you guys to remember this. Islam is,
我想让你们记住这点：伊斯兰是……
the power and
力量与
beauty comes from how Islam is
美感来自伊斯兰的
able to unite two major intellectual traditions in the world.
能够将世界两大知识传统统一起来
The first is paganism, right?
第一点是多神论，对吧？
Remember the Vikings? The Vikings told stories.
记得维京人吗？他们讲故事。
They acted out rituals. And therefore, there was an intimacy,
他们表演仪式，因此产生了亲密感。
concreteness, and interconnectedness to paganism
具体性与互联性，正如多神论所示
that made us feel happy and good.
让我们感到快乐与美好
Okay? It made us understand the world.
好的？它让我们理解世界
It made us feel as though we could influence the world.
它让我们觉得自己能影响世界。
That's the power of paganism. But Islam is doing the same thing.
这就是多神论的力量。可是伊斯兰也做了同样事。
By making God concrete.
把神具体化。
Okay? You can feel God.
好的？你能感受到神。
God is everywhere. He knows everything.
神无处不在，他无所不知。
But what Islam is also doing is,
而伊斯兰也在做的事是，
he's seeing the simplicity, clarity, and absoluteness of monotheism.
他看到了单神论的简洁、清晰与绝对性。
Okay? Monotheism is nice
好吧？单神论很不错。
because with monotheism, everything becomes clear to you.
因为有了单神论，一切都变得清晰可见。
Right? Okay, there's one God.
对吧？好的，只有一位神。
Therefore, I just have to follow him.
于是，我只需跟随他。
I just have to believe in him. There's like a million gods in paganism.
我只需信仰他。多神教里有上百万位神。
And so, it was unclear what you should do or how you should relate to this million gods.
于是，你不清楚该做什么，也不清楚该如何与这些万神相处。
But here in monotheism, the relationship between God
但在单神论里，神与…
and you, it's very, very clear.
而你，事情就非常非常清楚。
Okay? So in other words,
好的？换句话说，
Islam is a major
伊斯兰是一个主要
intellectual revolution in human history.
人类历史中的知识革命。
And we have forgotten this.
而我们已经忘记了这一点。
Because Islam, the idea,
因为伊斯兰，这个概念，已经嵌入现代性本身。
has embedded itself into modernity itself.
Okay? Does that make sense?
好的？这样说通吗？
All right. So,
好的。
what I will show you over the course of the semester is
我将在学期中展示的内容是
that Islam really is the portal of modernity.
伊斯兰真的是现代性的门户。
When we say that modernity began in Europe,
当我们说现代性起源于欧洲时，
we forget that Islam really built the basis
我们忘记了伊斯兰真正奠基
for modernity. Okay?
为现代性。好的吗？
All right? So, fulfillment of the law and profit.
好吧？于是，法律的实现与收益。
It's completing the story in the Bible.
它完成了圣经中的故事。
It's bringing God to the people.
它把神带给人们。
You can now touch God.
你现在可以触摸神。
You can now know God. That's the beginning of the idea of Protestantism.
你现在可以认识神。这是新教派思想的起点。
Okay? And create heaven on earth.
好吧？在地上创造天堂。
And this is the idea of science.
这就是科学的思想。
Why do we use science? To make the world better.
我们用科学做什么？是让世界更好。
Because God wants us to make the world better.
因为上帝想让我们让世界更好。
All right? So a lot of the ideas
好的？所以很多的想法
that will underpin modernity,
将会成为现代性的基础
that God can be in us, and that God expects us to make the world better,
神可以在我们之中，且神期盼我们让世界更好，
it's already there in the beginnings of Islam.
它已在伊斯兰的初期出现。
And that's why we will have the Islamic Golden Age.
这就是我们将迎来伊斯兰黄金时代的原因。
Because they are propelled by their devotedness to the one true God.
因为他们因对唯一真神的虔诚而被推动。
Is this clear to you guys? Any questions so far?
这点你们明白吗？到目前为止有无问题吗？
Any questions so far? All right.
到目前为止有无问题吗？好的。
So let me really quickly answer the three mysteries.
于是让我快速回答这三个谜题。
Okay? The first problem is, why were there no written records?
好的？第一个问题是，为什么没有书面记录？
The answer is, first of all, Islam marks a revolution.
答案是，首先，伊斯兰标志着一次革命。
Okay? It is overturning the social order.
好的？它正是推翻社会秩序。
The problem though is that eventually, Islam will become the social order.
问题在于，最终伊斯兰将成为社会秩序。
So you obviously don't want to paint Muhammad as a revolutionary.
于是你显然不想把穆罕默德描成革命者。
Okay? That's the first problem.
好的吗？那是第一个问题。
Muhammad represented a revolution
穆罕默德代表了一场革命
against the social order.
对社会秩序的革命。
All right? That's the first thing.
好了？那是第一个问题。
Second thing is that
第二个问题是……
we know that his early followers, the companions,
我们知道他的早期追随者，伙伴们……
were all wiped out. They're all dead.
全都被消灭了。他们全死了。
They all died. The official history says that,
他们全死了。官方史书说是这样，
they died in military conflicts.
他们在军事冲突中死亡。
But here's the amazing thing about early Islam history.
但关于早期伊斯兰史的惊人之处在于此。
We don't have that much evidence of military conflict
我们没有太多关于阿拉伯人与波斯人、拜占庭人之间的军事冲突证据。
between the Arabs and the Persians and the Byzantines.
We don't. There's maybe one city, Caesarea, where
我们没有。也许只有一个城市，凯撒里亚，曾经受围攻。
there was a siege.
但我们认为是这样。
But we think that
a lot of the conquest happened organically
大量征服是自然而成的
or maybe
或者说
their enemies surrendered to them rather than fight them.
他们的敌人投降而非交战
Okay? And that's why I would say it's a revolution.
好的？这就是我说它是革命的原因。
It's not a conquest.
不是一次征服。
It's a revolution where ordinary people
是一次普通人参与的革命。
were so disgusted with the current leadership that they opted for
他们对现任领导层十分失望，以此选择
a new belief system.
一个新的信仰体系。
Okay? The problem
好？问题在于。
though is that once you amass power
只要你聚集力量并形成联盟
and it's a coalition,
the question then is, who's now in charge?
问题是，谁现在掌权？
So for the next 50,
接下来50年……
100 years, there'll be a series of civil war to determine
100年后，将出现一系列内战来决定谁掌权。
who will be in charge.
谁将掌权。
Okay? Those early companions were probably purged.
好的？那些早期伙伴大概被清洗了。
The word we use is purged. They're wiped out, including the Jews and the Christians.
我们用的词是清洗。他们被消灭了，包括犹太人和基督徒。
We know for a fact that in the early days of Islam,
我们知道，伊斯兰早期，犹太人和基督徒已是层级的一部分。
Jews and Christians were part of the hierarchy.
There's a man named Saint John of Damascus
有一位叫做大马士干的圣约翰
who was very famous and he was a
他非常有名气
leader official in the Umayyad Caliphate.
领袖官在倭马伊德哈里斯帕特的官方职位。
We know that as a fact.
我们知道这点。
But eventually they were purged from the system.
但最终他们被从体系中清洗掉了。
And if they're purged, what happens is they're also purged of history.
如果他们被清洗，结果就是他们的历史也被清洗。
Okay? Because if these are the companions of Muhammad,
好的？因为如果这些是穆罕默德的同伴，基督徒和犹太人，那他们就是合法的。
Christians and Jews, then they're legitimate.
They're more legitimate than you are. So therefore they have to purge that history.
他们比你更合法。因此他们必须把那段历史清洗掉。
Okay? But knowing that, and the third thing is that
好吧？但知道了这一点，第三点是……
there'll be a series of continuous civil wars
随后会出现一连串的持续内战。
among the Arabs in order to determine
在阿拉伯人中确定谁将成为哈里发
who will be the caliph.
显然他们想掩盖这段历史。
And obviously they want to disguise this history.
And obviously they wantto disguise this history.
They want to disguise this history of civil conflict.
他们想掩盖这段内战历史。
Okay? So the first hundred years, it was revolutionary,
好吧？所以最初的百年，既是革命性的，
but it was also very tumultuous and bloody.
又非常动荡且血腥。
And that's why they had to disguise the first hundred years of Islamic history.
于是他们才需要掩盖伊斯兰历史的前百年。
All right? Does that make sense?
好吧？这样说通吗？
Get to your guys. And again, this is my explanation.
赶紧你们的伙伴们。再说一次，这是我的解释。
I could be wrong. All right?
我可能错了。好吧？
There could be other explanations.
也许还有其他解释。
Yeah? I'm just curious to throw in another idea.
嗯？我只是想再抛一个想法。
And I think what you said doesn't contradict this either.
我觉得你说的也不与此相冲突。
But one thing that's hard for us to imagine is
但有一点我们很难想象，
that our culture would actually be according to the history of other things.
我们的文化实际上会按其他事物的历史来解释。
It seems to us that it gets that theme, like the Chinese culture,
它似乎让我们觉得它获得了那个主题，就像中国文化一样，
the official historians going back for 20, 30 years.
官方史学家回溯20、30年。
But not every culture has a historian.
但并非每种文化都有史学家。
The Persians didn't write history.
波斯人没有写史书。
The Indians didn't write history. And
印度人也没有写史书。并且
I'm guessing the Arabs didn't have a
我猜测阿拉伯人也没有写史书。
tradition of writing down their history either.
他们也有记录历史的传统。
And so that this would actually be recorded in the sense
于是这件事就会按我们熟悉的方式被记录下来。
that we've been familiar with.
But probably wasn't the case.
但可能不是那样。
That is a great point.
这点很重要。
Thank you, Doug. So, so, so Doug's point is
谢谢你，Doug。于是，Doug的要点是
that the idea of history comes to us from the Greeks
历史观念从希腊人传来
and the Romans who wrote everything down.
以及记录一切的罗马人。
Okay? But as Doug says, there are many cultures
好的？但正如道格所说，已有许多文化。
who do not believe or do not, they don't have institutions to write down history.
他们不相信或不做事，他们没有机构来记录历史。
We sort of take it for granted today.
我们现在把这件事当作理所当然。
But back then, it was actually a pretty rare thing to actually want to write down your history.
但那时，真正想把自己的历史写下来其实相当罕见。
Okay? So, and the good, a good reason why is
好吧，好的，原因之一是…
that you write down the history,
写下历史，
you're writing down the history but you're also constrained by the history.
你写下历史，但也受历史约束。
Right? And, and that's why a lot of empires chose to not write down their history.
对吧，正因为如此，许多帝国选择不写下自己的历史。
Okay? So, so, so thank you. Yeah.
好吧，好吧，好吧，谢谢。
All right. Second question is,
好的。第二个问题是，
why didn't Muhammad name his successor?
为什么穆罕默德没有指定继任者？
Again, this is just my theory.
再说一次，这只是我的理论。
But if it's the end of days,
但如果是时代末日，
if it's the end of the world, you don't need to name your successor because God's coming.
如果是世界末日，你不需要指定继任者，因为上帝已来。
Right? What's the point?
对吧？有什么意义？
In fact, if you name your successor,
实际上，如果你指定继任者，
then you are admitting defeat.
然后你承认失败。
Right? What, what Muhammad is saying to everyone is
对吧？穆罕默德对大家说的是什么？
that every of your traditions,
就是你们各自的传统，
Jewish, Christian, Zoroastrian, are right.
犹太人、基督徒、祆教徒，皆正确。
It's the end of days. God is coming.
日子已至，神将临。
There'll be peace on the world. Therefore, we will no longer need leaders.
天下将安，故不再需领袖。
You won't need Muhammad. I'm the last prophet,
你不需要穆罕默德，我是最后的先知。
man. Okay?
人。好吧？
So that's, that's why I think, that's why I think he didn't name his successor.
所以就是，我想的原因，就是我认为他没给继任者起名。
But there could be other explanations.
但也可能还有其他解释。
Okay? Do, do, do you have another explanation?
好？你还有别的解释吗？
Okay. Now third is,
好的。第三点是，
why did they build the Al -Aqsaq Mosque on the second temple,
为什么他们在第二座圣殿上建了阿尔-阿克萨清真寺？
on the Temple Mount? And this explanation is going to be very controversial.
在圣殿山上？这个解释将会非常有争议。
Okay? So
好？
the Jews support the Persians in the war against
犹太人支持波斯人在对抗
the Byzantines on the condition
拜占庭人以条件为前提
that the Persians would allow them to return to Jerusalem,
波斯人会允许他们回到耶路撒冷。
but also on the condition that,
但也以……为条件。
that the Jews would be allowed to rebuild their temple.
犹太人将被允许重建他们的圣殿。
Which is exactly what Sars the Great did.
这正是萨尔斯大帝所做的事。
Right? Sars the Great is, it's called the Messiah in the Bible.
对吧？萨尔斯大帝，就是圣经里称为弥赛亚的人。
He's the only foreign leader called the Messiah in the Bible
他是圣经里唯一被称作弥赛亚的外族领袖。
because Sars the Great allowed them to rebuild the temple.
因为萨尔斯大帝让他们重建圣殿。
Okay? So what I'm saying is this,
好的？我说的是这样：
Al -Aqsaq Mosque was originally the third temple.
阿尔-阿克萨q清真寺最初是第三座圣殿。
It was, it is what the Arabs promised the Jews.
它就是阿拉伯人向犹太人所承诺的那座圣殿。
For the support.
为了支持。
But, over time,
但，随着时间的推移，
as these Persians happened, as civil conflicts happened,
随着这些波斯人出现，随着内战发生，
then the Arabs needed to consolidate their authority.
于是阿拉伯人需要巩固他们的权威。
So they turned the third temple into the Al -Aqsaq Mosque.
于是他们把第三座圣殿改建成阿尔-阿克萨q清真寺。
That's what I think happened. If you go into the,
我认为就是这样发生的。
I don't have time to go into the very detailed
我没有时间去详细阐述阿尔-阿克萨q清真寺的建造历史，
history of how the Al -Aqsaq Mosque was built,
但它是一个历时约200年的过程。
but it was a process that took about 200 years.
And it's very possible during these 200 years, intentions changed.
在这200年里，意图很可能发生了变化。
Okay? So again, I know this is an extremely controversial statement,
好的？所以，我知道这句话非常有争议，
but I think that's what happened.
我认为这就是事情的经过。
Originally, it was meant to be the third temple.
最初它是要成为第三座寺庙。
But then, over time,
随后，随着时间推移，
the Arab leaders changed their minds and thought to themselves
阿拉伯领袖们改主意，开始自我思考。
that if we do this, then
如果我们这么做，就能把犹太人变成在穆斯林世界里极具影响力的政治实体。
we make the Jews into very powerful
我们把犹太人变成在穆斯林世界里极具影响力的政治实体。
political entity within the Muslim world.
如果我们这么做，就能把犹太人变成在穆斯林世界里极具影响力的政治实体。
Okay? Does that make sense to you guys?
好的？你们觉得有道理吗？
Alright? Okay.
好的？行。
Again, like, these are my explanations.
再说一次，这些是我的解释。
It's my interpretation. This is not historical fact.
这是我的解读。这不是历史事实。
Okay? Alright. Now that we've done the three mysteries, let's go back to the three original questions.
好？行。现在我们已经解开了三大谜题，回到最初的三问。
First question is, why did Islam enter its golden age
第一个问题是，为什么伊斯兰进入其黄金时代。
and Christian Europe enter its dark age?
犹太教、基督教与伊斯兰教。
Second question is, why did the Islamic State enter its dark age?
第二个问题是，为什么伊斯兰国家进入其暗淡期？
Why did the Islamic State enter its golden age? And third question is, how did Christian Europe overtake the Muslim world?
第三个问题是，基督教欧洲是如何超越穆斯林世界的？
Okay. To answer these three questions,
好的。要回答这三个问题，只需把这三大宗教进行比较与对照。
all we have to do is compare and contrast
只要把这三大宗教进行比较与对照。
these three major religions together.
只需把这三大宗教进行比较与对照。
Judaism, Christianity, and Islam.
犹太教、基督教与伊斯兰教。
Alright? There are both strengths
好吧？各宗教都有优点和缺点。
and weaknesses to all religions.
So let's very quickly compare and
于是我们快速比较与对照这三大宗教，看看它们为何在特定历史背景中兴盛。
contrast these three major religions to see why they thrive in a certain historical context.
于是，犹太教。圣经，
So, Judaism. The Bible,
So, Judaism. TheBible,
it's a wonderful piece of literature.
它是一篇精彩的文学作品。
It has a very rich history going back a thousand years.
它拥有一千多年的丰富历史。
Right? So the Jews were the first to
对吧？所以犹太人是最早的…
have a complete history of themselves.
拥有完整的历史叙述。
There are beautiful stories
有美丽的故事
in the Bible that still inspire today.
在圣经中仍然激发今日灵感。
The stories of Adam and Eve.
亚当与夏娃的故事。
The stories of the patriarchs.
族长们的故事。
The story of Moses. They still inspire us today and they inspire us to create great literature.
摩西的故事。它们仍然激发我们，并激励我们创作伟大文学。
And then you have a literary culture.
于是你们拥有了文学文化。
So, the Jews were expected to be people of the book.
因此，犹太人被期望成为书卷之人。
They were expected to be literate
他们被期望具备读写能力。
in order to practice their religion.
为了实践他们的宗教。
Okay? And this helps us understand
好的？这帮助我们理解
why Jews are so dominant in academia,
犹太人在学术界如此占主导的原因。
universities, in the media and in culture, and in the legal profession.
大学、媒体、文化以及法律界。
Okay? Because these are people of the book. They have a tremendous respect for learning and for literacy.
好？因为这些人是书卷之人。他们对学习和读写有极大的敬意。
Okay? That said,
好？说到这里。
there are certain problems with the tradition.
有些传统存在问题。
The first is, it's contradictory.
第一个是它自相矛盾。
When you read the Bible, it's always contradicting itself.
读圣经时，它总是自相矛盾。
Okay? It's almost schizophrenic, you could say.
好？可以说几乎是精神分裂。
It's very hard to pick out a definite message
很难从圣经中挑出一个确定的信息。
from the Bible. And that's why the old tradition
这就是古老传统的原因。
called the Torah is actually much more important.
被称为《托拉》的其实更重要。
Okay? And so Jews have to go
好？于是犹太人就得一直去。
to the synagogue all the time
去会堂。
where the rabbi will explain to them the meaning of the Bible.
在这里，拉比会向他们解释圣经的含义。
Because if you read it by yourself it's almost impossible to understand.
因为如果你自己读的话，几乎难以理解。
Okay? Second problem is
好？第二个问题是…
their God, Yahweh, He's very problematic.
他们的神雅威，他非常麻烦。
He's extremely problematic.
他极其麻烦。
As we know from last semester when we looked at the Bible.
正如上学期我们研究圣经时所知。
He doesn't seem to know what He's doing.
他似乎不知道自己在干什么。
And He's very, very
他非常、非常……
violent. Okay? He often commands the Israelites to go kill all their enemies.
他很暴力。好？他常常命令以色列人去杀死所有敌人。
Okay? So he's a very problematic God.
好的？他是个非常麻烦的神。
The third major problem in the tradition is
传统中的第三大问题是
faith versus history.
信仰与历史。
If you believe that you are the chosen people,
如果你认为自己是被选民，
if you believe that Yahweh is the only true God,
如果你认为雅威是唯一真神，
then why are you being persecuted all the time?
那为什么你总是被迫害？
Why were the Romans able to kick you out of Jerusalem
为什么罗马人能把你踢出耶路撒勒并烧毁你的圣殿，那里是神的居所？
and burn down your temple, which is the house of God?
你为什么无家可归？
Why are you homeless?
Why do you lack a homeland?
你为什么没有故乡？
And this has been going on for thousands of years.
这已经持续了数千年。
And there are no easy explanations to any of these problems.
这些问题没有简单的解释。
So within the Jewish faith,
在犹太信仰中，
there's a lot of conflict and debate and doubt. So
有许多冲突、辩论与疑惑。于是
the Christian faith was created in many ways to try to resolve a lot of the issues within the Jewish tradition.
基督信仰以多种方式诞生，试图解决犹太传统中的诸多问题。
The first major advantage of the Christian faith is it's the perspective.
基督教的第一个主要优势是它的视角。
It's the justification and perfection of divinity.
它是对神性的证明与完善。
Remember how we said that Yahweh is problematic?
记得我们说过雅威是有问题的吧。
Well, now we have Jesus who we can understand.
好了，现在我们有了耶稣，我们可以理解他。
And Jesus made the ultimate sacrifice.
耶稣献上了终极牺牲。
Therefore we know him to be the ultimate good.
于是我们知道他是终极之善。
Second advantage is now that there's a person,
第二个优势是现在有了一个人，
we can for him deliver a consistent message of being kind,
我们可以为他传递一条连贯的善良信息，
being merciful, being loving.
仁慈、爱意的消息。
The third advantage is, we can for him deliver a consistent message of being kind,
第三个优势是我们可以为他传递一条连贯的善良信息，
such as such
如同样的
such such
同样的
如此
such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such
如同样的
such such such such such such such such such such such
such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such
如同样的
such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such such The first issue is,
第一个问题是，
it's a really confusing story.
这真是个让人困惑的故事。
Why would God come down to earth,
为什么上帝会降临人间，
manifest himself as a human, and then sacrifice himself?
显现为人，随后自我牺？
That's really, really confusing.
这真是，真是困惑。
Like, I know there's a lot of really good explanations as to why this is the case.
像，我知道有很多很好的解释说明这是原因。
Still, if you're just a normal person,
还是，如果你只是普通人，
you can't understand the story.
你不懂这个故事。
It makes no sense to you, okay? Second is that it's counterintuitive.
对你来说没道理，第二点是它反直觉。
A lot of the ideas in Christianity, it's just counterintuitive.
基督教里很多想法都很反直觉。
The Holy Trinity must be the strangest idea in religion,
圣三位一体是宗教里最奇怪的概念。
where God, the Holy Spirit, and
哪里上帝、圣灵与耶稣分离却同等。
Jesus are separate but equal.
它对任何人都没有直观意义。
It makes no intuitive sense to anyone.
And the third is distant divinity, okay?
第三点是远方的神性，好的？
God is out there somewhere.
神在那边的某处。
You don't know where. You can't talk to him.
你不知道在哪。你无法与他对话。
You can't see him.
你看不见他。
You have to know. You have no idea where he is, okay?
你得知道。你根本不知道他在哪，行吗？
It's a very distant divinity.
它是非常遥远的神性。
And so, these are the disadvantages of Christianity.
于是，基督教的这些就是它的缺点。
And so, Islam now makes sense because it's trying to remedy
于是，伊斯兰现在才有意义，因为它试图补救并纠正基督教的缺陷。
and rectify these failings of Christianity, okay?
The first is that it takes the Jewish tradition
第一点是它把犹太传统和基督传统纳入自身，行吗？
and the Christian tradition and makes it part of itself, okay?
第二点是神的绝对性，行吗？
So, it is really the continuation and
于是，它确实是犹太-基督传统的延续与完善。
the perfection of the Jewish -Christian tradition.
它是犹太-基督传统的延续与完善。
The second is the absoluteness of God, okay?
第二点是神的绝对性，行吗？
This is now true monotheism,
这就是现在的单一神论。
where God is everywhere.
在上帝无处不在的地方。
And you can see him.
你可以看到他。
But if God is everywhere, then what's amazing is
但如果上帝无处不在，那么令人惊讶的是
that you can now, that
你现在可以了，那
God can come inside you through your faith,
上帝可以通过你的信仰、奉献和实践进入你体内。
through your devotion, and through your practice.
All right? And so,
好的？那样，
what this means is you now know how to behave in the world.
这意味着你现在知道如何在世界里行动。
There's a clarity of purpose and action.
有了明确的目标和行动。
You know that as long as you do those five things,
你知道，只要做这五件事，
those five pillars of Islam, your life will be good.
这五根伊斯兰支柱，你的生活就会好起来。
God is in you.
上帝在你里面。
And that gives you strength and purpose and power, okay?
这给你力量、目的和权力，好吗？
And these ideas is what will start the Islamic Golden Age
这些理念就是开启伊斯兰黄金时代的起点
and allow Islam to propel itself past everyone, okay?
并让伊斯兰在众人之上腾飞，好吗？
The problem, though, is it's...
问题是它……
Too simple and clear.
太简单明了
The advantage of being contradictory is
矛盾的优势是
you allow for different belief systems,
你允许不同的信仰体系出现，
which come into conflict with each other.
它们彼此相互冲突。
And with this contradiction and
并且伴随此矛盾，
conflict, it allows for innovation.
冲突，它为创新留出了空间。
That's why Catholicism will eventually give way to Protestantism,
这就是为什么天主教最终会让位给新教，
okay? Which
好的？哪一个
is a reinterpretation of the Bible.
是对圣经的重新诠释。
But it's because of Bible.
但这因圣经而成。
The Bible is so contradictory that
圣经如此自相矛盾，以致。
this innovation is not to happen.
这项创新并未发生。
The Bible was extremely clear.
圣经非常清晰。
The Quran is extremely clear. But if that's the case,
古兰经也非常清晰。
then you cannot allow for radical rejection of the past
然后你就不能对过去的根本性放弃，才能拥抱未来，行吗？
and embrace of the future, okay?
第二个问题是它的刚性。
Second problem, then, is it's inflexible.
It can't be as innovative as Christianity and Judaism.
它不像基督教和犹太教那样具有创新性。
The third problem is it's Islam.
第三个问题是伊斯兰。
And the third problem is that the Islamic religion purports to stand outside of history, okay?
而第三个问题是伊斯兰宗教自称处于历史之外，好吗？
Judaism is to be inside of history.
犹太教属于历史之中。
Christianity is inside of history as well.
基督教亦属于历史之中。
But Islam is eternal.
而伊斯兰则是永恒的。
When you read the Koran, it's meant to be the eternal words.
当你读《可兰经》时，它被视为永恒之词。
These words are always true.
这些词永远真实。
But then the problem then is...
但随后问题出现了…
How do you go about and interpret...
你是怎样去做并通过历史视角来解释自己的行动？
your actions through the lens of history?
你又是怎样基于这种解释来提升自己的社会？
And how do you improve your society based on this interpretation?
你是怎样去做并通过历史视角来解释自己的行动？
All right? So
好的？那么
in the beginning, the very aspects,
一开始，伊斯兰的各个方面，
the very strengths of Islam will give rise to a tremendous period of creativity.
伊斯兰的各项优势将孕育出一个巨大的创造期。
But over time, you will have...
但随着时间推移，你会有……
These innovations will become dogma.
这些创新将成为教条。
And they will ossify, and they will prevent further growth in your society.
它们会变得僵化，并阻碍你社会的进一步发展。
All right? So does that make sense to you guys?
好吧？这样说对你们有意义吗？
All right. So let me reframe what I just said in a different way.
好吧。让我用另一种方式重新表述刚才说的内容。
All right? So let's just compare...
好吧？那我们就直接比较一下……
Sorry. Let's...
抱歉。让我们……
Sorry. So I'm going to compare and contrast
抱歉。于是我要比较并对照……
Christianity with Islam.
基督教与伊斯兰教。
And then this will be a bit more clear.
然后这会更清晰一点。
Clear to you. All right?
清楚吗？好吧？
But are there any questions before I continue?
继续之前你们有问题吗？
Is this clear to you guys? So I apologize.
这对你们来说清楚吗？我先道个歉。
I'm making a lot of generalizations.
我在做很多概括。
But again, this is a macro view of history.
但这又是历史的宏观。
All right. So let's look at Christianity
好的。我们先看基督教。
and compare it with Islam.
再与伊斯兰比较。
All right? So
好的？
as I have said in previous classes,
正如我在前几课所说，
Christianity was developed by the Roman Empire in order to co -opt first the Jews
基督教是由罗马帝国发展而成，目的是先合并犹太人，
and eventually these barbarian invaders.
随后再合并这些蛮族入侵者。
And therefore, the religion is one of empire
因此，宗教是帝国的一项
and power.
和权力。
Okay? Okay? It's really about how to control people.
好吧？好吧？这就是关于如何控制人们的事。
But Islam, as I just mentioned,
但正如我刚才提到的，伊斯兰是……
it is a revolutionary religion that
它是一种革命性的宗教
must be open and inclusive and
必须开放包容并且
tolerant in order to attract as many followers as possible.
容忍以吸引尽可能多的信徒。
All right? Now,
好了？现在，
the main mechanism of control for an
主要的控制机制是
empire is the idea of orthodoxy.
帝国即正统之意。
Orthodoxy just means the correct thinking.
正统仅指正确的思考。
Okay? But if you're orthodoxy, then you have the idea of heresy.
好的？但如果你是正统的，那你就有异端的想法。
Okay? So, orthodoxy is with God.
好的？所以，正统就是与上帝同在。
Heresy is against God.
异端是对上帝的。
If you agree that the sky is red, because I say the sky is red, then you are orthodox.
如果你同意天空是红色，因为我说天空是红色，那么你就是正统的。
But if you insist the sky is blue, then it is heretical.
如果你坚持天空是蓝色，那就是异端。
Okay? And that constrains or limits the imagination.
好吧？而这又限制了想象。
All right? And
好的？然后
the philosopher that
那位哲学家
you base your society on is Plato.
你把社会的基础设在柏拉图上。
Plato. So, the idea of the bishop,
柏拉图。所以，主教的想法，
the idea of the pope, it's really the idea of Plato's philosopher king.
教皇的想法，真的是柏拉图哲学家之王的想法。
All right? So,
好吧？所以，
I'll explain Plato's philosophy in a second.
我稍后会解释柏拉图的哲学。
Okay? But let's look at Islam.
好的？那我们来看看伊斯兰。
So, it's a revolutionary religion, and
于是，它是一种革命性的宗教，且
therefore, you must activate the energy of all your followers.
于是，你必须激活所有信徒的能量。
You must get them to believe, and you must get them to fight.
你必须让他们相信，并让他们去战斗。
Therefore, it's a religion based on intuition.
于是，它是一种基于直觉的宗教。
God is a religion based on intuition. God is with you.
上帝是一种基于直觉的宗教。上帝与你同在。
You know God. God is inside you.
你已知上帝。上帝在你之内。
Okay? And the idea of intuition is what allows for science.
好的？直觉的概念正是让科学得以诞生的根源。
You can discover the truth by just observing,
你只需观察即可发现真理，
through empirical observation,
通过经验观察即可。
through your own analysis,
通过你自己的分析，
through your own belief.
通过你自己的信念，
Okay? And the person who argues this is, of course, Aristotle.
好的？而且提出此论点的人，当然是亚里士多德。
So, this is the argument I'm making to you.
于是，我向你提出的论点就是这个。
Okay? A lot of scholars believe,
好吧？许多学者认为，
that the Islamic Golden Age happened
伊斯兰的黄金时代确实发生了。
because the Islamic Golden, the Islams had books.
因为伊斯兰的黄金时代，伊斯兰人拥有书籍。
They had wealth. But
他们拥有财富。但
the Byzantines also had access to all these major thinkers,
拜占庭人也能接触这些主要思想家
Plato and Aristotle. They all, Byzantines had a lot of wealth.
柏拉图与亚里士多德。他们都，拜占庭人拥有大量财富。
Okay? What I'm arguing is that
好吧？我正在论证的是……
a culture needs to have a attitude,
一个文化需要有一种态度，
a perspective, a worldview, an orientation.
一种视角、世界观和取向。
For the Byzantines and the Europeans, they chose Plato.
对拜占庭人和欧洲人来说，他们选择了柏拉图。
But the Muslims chose Aristotle.
而穆斯林则选择了亚里士多德。
And that is the major difference.
而这就是主要区别。
Okay? So let's go over,
好吧？那我们来回顾一下，
let's summarize Plato and Aristotle.
让我们总结一下柏拉图和亚里士多德。
How were the philosophies different?
两者的哲学有何不同？
Okay. For Plato,
好的。对柏拉图来说，真正的上帝被称为善的形式。
the true God is called the form of the good.
the true God is calledthe form of the good.
The form of the good is the beginning.
善的形式是起点。
The beginning of everything. It is what is immutable.
万物的起点。它是不变的。
That cannot be changed. It is perfect.
它不变，完美无缺。
And it's eternal. Eternal means it was always there
而它是永恒的。永恒就是它一直存在。
and it will always be there.
并且它永远在。
The form of the good, this God,
善的形式，这个上帝。
he thinks and he emanates new concepts,
他思考并发出新概念，
called ideals, like justice, reason,
称之为理想，如正义、理性
beauty, power. Okay?
美丽，力量。好吗？
And these ideals will manifest themselves into,
这些理想将化为……
perfect forms. Okay?
完美的形态。好吗？
Like a horse, like a perfect horse, the perfect woman, okay?
像马，像完美的马，完美的女人，好吗？
This we can say is just heaven.
这可以说是天国。
We live in something called a shadow world,
我们生活在一个叫影子世界的地方。
which is just an imitation of heaven.
这只是天国的模仿。
It's a bad imitation, so everything sucks, okay?
是个糟糕的模仿，全部都糟糕，好吗？
So for example, if you fall down and you break your leg, it hurts.
比如说，你摔倒了，腿折了，疼。
It hurts. Because we live in a shadow world.
疼，因为我们生活在影子世界里。
So in this conception of the universe,
在这种宇宙观里，
what we're trying to do is
我们要做的事是
return to the form of the good.
回到善的形相。
And for Plato, he argues that you can do this through mathematics and geometry.
而且对柏拉图来说，他认为你可以通过数学和几何来做到这一点。
Because mathematics is what is most like the form of the good.
因为数学最像善的形相。
It is immutable, perfect, and eternal.
它是不变的、完美的、永恒的。
So by studying mathematics and geometry,
于是通过学习数学和几何，
you are able to ascend back, into the form of the good.
你就能再次升入善的形相。
But guess what?
但你猜怎么回事？
Augustine will take Plato and he will adapt it to the Christian faith.
奥古斯丁会把柏拉图带进来，并把它改编成基督教信仰。
Right? Because how do you leave this world?
对吧？因为你怎么离开这世界呢？
By not sinning.
不犯罪就行。
By having faith.
凭有信仰。
If you do that, then you are allowed to go to heaven.
若你这样做，就能去天国。
Okay? So
好吧？
in the Platonic Augustine understanding,
在柏拉图式的奥古斯丁理解中，
we in this world just, we are not allowed to go to heaven.
我们在这个世界里只是正直的，我们才有机会去天国。
We, all we have to do is not make a mistake.
我们，所有我们要做的就是不犯错。
So do nothing. Okay?
那就什么也不做。好吧？
Do nothing and you'll be good.
不做就会好。
Aristotle has a different conception of the universe.
亚里士多德对宇宙有另一种观念。
He believes the form of the good is called a prime mover.
他认为善的形式叫做第一动者。
All right? God is a prime mover.
好的？上帝是第一动者。
So God is the first thing that acts and moves things.
于是上帝就是第一动作并运动万物的存在。
Okay? And when he does that, when he creates motion,
好的？当他这么做时，创造运动，其他事物也会随之发生。
other things start to happen as well.
好的？于是我们不断地在运动。
Okay? So we're constantly moving about.
好的？我们一直在移动。
Where we're going is we are seeking truth.
我们要去的地方是寻找真理。
And it's called telos.
它被称为telos。
Telos means purpose.
telos就是目的。
So each of us, our nature has a purpose.
所以我们每个人的本性都有一个目的。
If you're, if you're a soldier, your purpose is to be the best warrior.
如果你是个士兵，你的目的就是成为最优秀的战士。
If you're a mathematician, your purpose is to be the best mathematician.
如果你是个数学家，你的目的就是成为最优秀的数学家。
Okay? And that is the idea.
好的？那就是这个想法。
The idea of truth.
真理的想法。
To fulfill your purpose.
实现你的目的。
And therefore, you must be constantly acting.
于是，你必须不断行动。
Okay? Now the, the beauty of this idea of motion is,
好吧？现在，这个运动概念的美妙之处在于，
you can now study it through empirical observation.
你可以通过经验观察来研究它。
You can observe things and then start to understand their nature.
你可以先观察事物，然后开始理解它们的本质。
And this gives rise to the idea of science.
这就产生了科学的概念。
Okay? Right?
好吧？对吧？
So, the Muslim world had a decidedly Aristotelian perspective,
于是，穆斯林世界有着明显的亚里士多德视角，
whereas the European world had a Platonic perspective.
而欧洲世界则有着柏拉图视角。
Now, the great thing about history,
现在，历史的伟大之处在于，
the great thing about civilization is, that what will happen is,
文明的伟大之处在于，接下来会发生的事是，
the Europeans will learn from the Muslims.
欧洲人会从穆斯林那里学到东西。
They'll copy the Muslims.
他们会复制穆斯林的做法。
Right? They'll bring back Aristotle.
对吧？他们会把亚里士多德带回来。
They'll bring back science.
他们会把科学带回来。
And they'll bring back intuition.
他们会把直觉带回来。
Alright? And they will do so
对吧？他们会这么做。
through three major events.
通过三件大事。
The first is the Renaissance.
第一件是文艺复兴。
Where they bring back Aristotle.
他们会把亚里士多德带回来。
The second is the Protestant Reformation.
第二件是新教改革。
Where they will bring back God.
他们会把神带回来。
Remember, the Catholic religion, God is aloof.
记住，天主教里，神是高远的。
God can only be understood through the!
神只能通过……来理解！
Pope or the priest.
教皇或神父。
Okay? But the Protestant religion is, no, God is with us.
好的？但新教宗教是，没错，神与我们同在。
God is in us. For your actions,
神在我们之中。凭你的行动，
you can win God's favor.
你就能赢得神的恩宠。
Okay? The last is science.
好的？最后是科学。
Right? The scientific revolution. And
对吗？科学革命。还有
these are the three major events
这些是三大事件
that will give us modernity.
那将赋予我们现代性。
Okay? But, guess what?
好吧？但，猜猜？
The Europeans are just
欧洲人刚刚
emulating the Muslims.
模仿穆斯林。
But, and this is really important,
好吧，且这点很重要，
they will improve on the Muslims.
他们会在穆斯林基础上再创新。
Okay? So the problem with science is, yes,
好吧？科学的问题是，嗯，在开始时你会有所有这些巨大的发现。
in the beginning you will have all this tremendous discovery.
但这项创新最终会导致一种叫做教条的东西。
But this innovation will eventually lead to something called dogma.
好的？所以你需要做的事是，创建机构来消除教条。
Alright? And so what you need to do,
好吧？接下来你要做的事是，
is create institutions to destroy dogma.
创建机构来消除教条。
And that's what the Europeans will do.
这就是欧洲人要做的事。
Which will, and this idea that
这将会，且这个想法是
dogma can be destroyed through discussion
教条可以通过讨论、辩论和分析来消除
and debate and analysis, is what will become the basis of the scientific revolution.
这将成为科学革命的基础
Which will create the modern world that we live in today. Okay?
这将创造我们今天所生活的现代世界。好吧？
So we will go through all of these three major movements in future classes.
接下来我们将在未来的课上逐一讲解这三大运动。
But, please remember,
但请记住，
that it's the Islamic Golden Age,
那是伊斯兰黄金时代，
which will inspire the Europeans
它将激发欧洲人
to do all three of these things.
去完成这三件事。
Which in turn, will create the modern world that we live in today.
这将造就我们今天所生活的现代世界。
Okay? And that's why I believe that the Islamic Golden Age is really,
好吧？这就是我认为伊斯兰黄金时代真正是人类历史现代化的门户。
is really the portal to modernity of human history.
Alright. That is my argument to you.
好的。那是我给你的论点。
Any questions? Anything you aren't clear about?
还有问题吗？还有不明白的地方吗？
Was this clear? Okay.
这说清楚了吗？好的。
I don't know if it's a question or just an observation, but...
我不知道是问句还是观察，反正是……
Sure. Are you able to go back a couple slides to the...
好的。你能回到前面几张幻灯片吗？
Sure. To the Empire and Power versus the Revolution.
好的。回到“帝国与权力与革命”那一张。
Okay. Sure.
好的。好的。
Right here. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
就在这里。是的，是的，是的。
So it's like one thing that you've gotten to know, and
所以这就像是你已经知道的一件事，
I was thinking about the theory here today as well.
我今天也在想这理论。
And so there's kind of two movements.
于是有两种运动。
Like the first one is like the...
第一种像是……
When we had Talmud, it was last about 100 years.
当我们拥有塔木德时，持续了大约100年。
Right. And it was really kind of
好的。它确实是那场帕特里克提到的革命。
that revolution that Patrick talked about.
那场革命正是帕特里克所说的那种革命。
Like very expansive growth, very, very quick.
像极其扩张的增长，极其迅速。
But it was also very Arab.
但它也极其阿拉伯。
Right? It was done by the Arabs.
对吗？是阿拉伯人完成的。
Okay? And what's really interesting is like if you look at the Abbasid Talmud,
好的？更有趣的是，如果你看阿巴斯王朝的塔木德……
the Talmud that comes afterwards,
随后出现的塔木德，
as Mr.
如先生
Jain said, it moves to Zaytab.
贾因说，它移到贾伊塔布。
And right now we think of Zaytab in Iraq as an Arab place.
现在我们把贾伊塔布视为伊拉克的阿拉伯之地。
But at that time it was Persian.
但那时它是波斯的。
And by moving there,
并且通过迁移到那里，
it represents partly a change in culture
它部分代表了文化的变迁
and moving away from an Arab homeland, basically.
并基本上离开阿拉伯故土
Right? So there's a whole bunch of...
对吧？所以有一大堆……
There's an amazing cultural openness,
有一种惊人的文化开放性，
there's contacts, like you said, with India,
有联系，正如你所说，与印度……
Central Asia.
中亚。
Islam moves into Central Asia.
伊斯兰进入中亚。
There's more contact with China and so on.
与中国等的接触更为频繁。
And there's a real cultural dynamism going on there.
并且那里的文化正蓬勃发展。
And Islam has to be very open to those cultures
伊斯兰必须对这些文化保持极大开放性。
and be inspired by those cultures
并从中汲取灵感。
and engage with them in a pretty deep way.
并以相当深入的方式与之互动。
Right? So in some ways it's not just the religion that's the
对吧？所以在某些方面，黄金时代的决定因素不只是宗教，而是……
deciding factor or what makes it a golden age, but
……
just being able to draw on so many different traditions
只要能汲汲多种不同传统的精华
and rich traditions in a way
并以此丰富的传统为基底
that, say, the Byzantines did or in Western Europe,
比如说，拜占庭人做了什么，或者在西欧…
you know, the Catholics that...
你知道，天主教会做了什么…
Right. Yeah, that's a great point.
对，好的，正是这个点。
So let me elaborate on this point.
让我再详细说明一下这个点。
So there's a literary critic, Norfolk Frye.
于是有位文学评论家，诺福克·弗赖。
Right? Yep.
对吧？是的。
Canadian. Right? So
加拿大人。对吧？所以
Norfolk Frye is a Canadian literary critic, okay?
弗赖是加拿大文学评论家，没错吗？
And one thing that he's obsessed about is how literature is developed.
他最着迷的一个点是文学是如何发展的。
What he's observed is there's a certain moment in history
他观察到的是历史上有一个特定的时刻。
when great literature comes about.
当伟大文学出现时。
And the moment is when
而时刻是当
a nation or a people or a culture
一个民族或一个民族群体或一个文化
becomes an empire.
成为帝国。
Okay? And the idea here is, okay,
好的？这里的意思是，好吧，
with a nation you have tradition.
有了民族就有了传统。
You have cohesion. Okay?
你有凝聚力。好吧？
You have a certain literary basis.
你有一定的文学基础。
Right? And then when it becomes an empire, it's forced to have a vista.
然后当它成为帝国时，必须拥有视野。
It's forced to have, like, a global perspective. And
它必须拥有一种全球视野。然后
this change from a nation or
从民族或
coherent people into a cosmopolitan empire,
统一的人群转变为世界性帝国，
at this stage in history,
在历史的这个阶段，
you can, it's possible for them to produce great literature.
你可以，能让他们创作出伟大的文学。
Okay? And there are many examples of this.
好吧？并且有许多例子。
So the first example, of course, is Athens.
首先的例子当然是雅典。
Athens is the civilization par excellence.
雅典是文明的典范。
Right? And so when
对吧？
did Athens produce all its great, like, literature?
雅典产生了所有伟大的文学吗？
Well, it was basically the age of Pericles, which lasted from,
嗯，基本上是柏拉克斯时代，从……开始
like, you know, 500 to about 400.
大约公元前500年到400年左右。
Okay? Maybe 350.
对吧？大约350年。
Okay? But it was not that long.
对吧？但并不长这么久。
And this is important because, you know, this period is also when
而这点重要，因为……这个时期也是……
Athens, which was a, you know,
雅典，那个你知道的，很小的城邦，突然变成了帝国。
a very small polis, suddenly became an empire.
它的转变促使它向外拓展。
And it was this transition that forced it to look outwards.
这就是它转向外部的原因。
Okay? So Athens is one example.
好的？所以雅典就是一个例子。
But then, of course, you have King David
但随后，当然，你会想到大卫王。
and the Israelites.
还有以色列人。
And again, after the Bronze Age collapse,
再一次，在青铜时代崩溃之后，
David was able to, like,
大卫王像是这样，
create a, an Israelite nation and then conquer a lot of this territory.
他建立了一个以色列民族并征服了大量领土。
So this, these people now were a small empire.
于是，这些人现在是一个小帝国。
They weren't a great empire. They were a small empire.
他们不是大帝国，而是小帝国。
Okay? And the last example that we have is England.
最后一个例子是英格兰。
Right? Think of Shakespeare.
对吧？想想莎士比亚。
When was Shakespeare writing? Around the year 1600.
莎士比亚写作的时间？大约1600年。
Okay? And that was when England, which
对吧？那时英格兰……
for the longest time was this poor island,
为最长时间，这个小岛屈居于此，
was now becoming, emerging as a global empire.
此时正成为，崛起为全球帝国。
And with it, a cosmopolitan perspective.
随之而来的是世界观的视角。
Right? So this is the pattern in history,
对吧？这就是历史的模式，
which picks up on Doug's point,
正好接上Doug的观点，
where the new Islamic empire,
新兴的伊斯兰帝国，
when they shifted their capital to Baghdad,
当他们把首都迁至巴格达时，
they now became a global empire.
此时他们已成为全球帝国。
And as such, they had to absorb all these different traditions
于是他们必须吸收所有这些不同的传统。
and cultures and become, a multicultural universal empire.
并且文化融合，形成多元化的世界帝国。
All right? So, Norbert Frey has made this observation.
对吧？于是诺伯特·弗雷作出了这一观察。
It sounds convincing.
听起来很有说服力。
I, I haven't,
我，我还没有，
I haven't done enough research to fully buy into this theory.
我还没有做足够的研究来完全相信这个理论。
Okay? But, but he has made this argument.
好的？不过，他确实提出了这个论点。
And he has made these observations with these examples.
他用这些例子做出了这些观察。
All right? So, thanks for that.
对吧？谢谢。
Okay. Any more questions? Okay.
好的。还有问题吗？
Okay. Okay. Okay. Okay.
好的。好的。好的。好的。
Okay. Okay.
好的。好的。
Okay. Okay. Okay. Okay. Okay.
好的。好的。好的。好的。好的。
Okay. Okay. Okay.
好的。好的。好的。
Okay. Okay. Okay. Okay. Okay. Okay. Okay.
好的。好的。好的。好的。好的。好的。好的。
Okay. So next class will be on the Middle Kingdom, China.
好的。下一节课是关于中原，中华。
And after that, we will do the Mongols.
然后我们会讲蒙古人。
And after that, we will return to Europe and
随后我们会回到欧洲，继续讲述。
do the Crusades.
再来我们会讲十字军。
Then we'll do the Renaissance, the Protestant Reformation, and the Sino -Semitic Revolution, OK?
然后我们会讲文艺复兴、宗教改革和中西革命，好的？